VICTOR WILLIAMS

Senior Software Engineer // Project Manager

vaporjawn.dev/

victor.williams.dev@gmail.com

Jan. 2021 - Present

June 2020 - Jan. 2021

OBJECTIVE

Full-stack software developer with strong analytical skills and proficiency in mathematics. Has an ability to follow established procedures and work under little or no supervision. Expertise in writing full-stack code to support multiple platforms, including web, android, and iOS, and a strong grasp of MVC, data structures, and object-oriented designs. Software development life cycle experience and team management experience.

EDUCATION -

Temple University, Philadelphia, PA May 2019

- Bachelor of Arts: Computer Science and Criminal Justice Certificate: Computer Security
- Studied the subjects of Discrete Mathematics, Differential Calculus, Data Structures, Algorithms, and Operating Systems within the Computer Science Curriculum

EXPERIENCE

Racing Unleashed

Senior Software Engineer / Project Manager

• Involved in writing application level code to interact with Web Services using Ajax, JSON, and XML. Deploying and testing features to the Azure Cloud

- Designed and developed a fully integrated electron launcher application
- Worked on 10 separate project repositories
- Created an application for platform integration for the client side
- Maintained the company website in all aspects (FullStack, Cloud, CMS)
- Skills: TypeScript, React, Electron, PHP, Craft CMS, Docker, CI/CD Pipelines, Avro Schemas, C#, Auth0

Context Capital Partners

Full Stack Application Developer

- Involved in writing application level code to interact with Web Services using Ajax, JSON, and XML. Deploying and testing features to the Azure Cloud
- Developed and tested a web application with successful production launch
- Created and maintained fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment
- Assisted in repository management
- Skills: React, Git, TypeScript, .NETCore, Integromat, Azure, SCRUM, JavaScript, C#

ACTIVITIES -

Temple University

Development Team -Eboard, Computer Science Tutor (TU), (ACM) Association for Computing Machinery, Scrum Alliance, (MLH) Major League Hacking. PennApps at UPenn, Alliance for Minority Participation in STEM. The Odyssey Online, Let's Get Ready SAT Prep Program, Owlchestra, Violinist

ORGANIZATIONS

Github Developer Program, Google Analytics, HackNY, TUDev, MLH Fellows, AmeriCorps, HackRU Let's Get Ready, Big Brother Big Sister, ACM, PennApps

BankMobile

Jan. 2020 – June 2020

Full Stack Software Engineer

- Architecture and development of REST services powered web-based SaaS application
- Web, iOS, and Android applications
- Worked in scrum process attending daily stand up and completing tasks in sprints
- A hand in both web and mobile development
- Collaborated on a large scale of developers based around the globe
- Skills: .NET, Xamarin, Angular.JS, C#, RESTfulAPI, Azure, SCSS, SQL, Swift, JavaScript, JSON, Visual Studio

AmeriCorps July. 2019 – Dec. 2019

Information Technology Manager / Web Developer

- Refined and improved the existing documentation within the system
- Reduced number of open tickets by 87% by prioritizing all open issues
- Updated several School District websites from AngularJS to ReactJS
- Managed a tech team and all technology in Taggart John H. School
- Skills: Angular.JS, React, Vue, API, Cloud, JSON, HTML5, CSS, Vue, MongoDB

BitGamer Nov. 2018 – Nov. 2019

Full Stack Software Engineer / Lead Tournament Organizer

- Developed a tournament hosting web application along with a small team
- Lead a geographically distributed team with large and small scale projects
- Wrote a series of technical documents to help speed up new engineer onboarding
- Managed social media for the company and performed quality analysis
- Skills: React.js, Node.js, RESTfulAPI, .NETCore, AWS, Visual Studio, Java, Python, HTML5

CrystalFruit

Dec. 2016 – Mar. 2019

Full Stack Software Engineer

- Implemented solutions using Agile (SCRUM) methodology
- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data
- Lead a team of 3 software engineers, creating roadmap definitions, established engineering best practices and mentored other members of the team
- Maintained and updated websites upon request per client, held meetings with team and end users to discuss product planning
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software
- Skills: Bootstrap, Vue.js, ASP.NET, React, .NETCore, MVC, MongoDB, Git, API, PHP, Vue, Ruby, HTML5, CSS, Go, Node.js, JSON